https://www.rams.com.au/about-rams/privacy/

Due to scheduled maintenance, myRAMS (online and mobile) will be unavailable from 10pm Saturday 12
December to 12 am Sunday 13 December (Sydney time).
We apologise for any inconvenience caused.
Toggle navigation
more
RAMS
Call: 13 RAMS
Home LoansHome loan interest ratesCompare our home loansFlexible featuresValue Advantage PackageFirst home buyersEssential home loanFixed rate home loansFull feature home loanLine of creditSelf-employedAll home loansRefinancersInvestorsCustomersSavings & TransactionsRAMS SaverRAMS ActionRAMS Action with OffsetInsuranceKnowledge CentreAll topicsBuilding a homeBuying a propertyInvestingManaging financesRefinancingRenovatingCalculators & ResourcesAll calculatorsBorrowingRepaymentsStamp dutyUpfront & ongoing costsEquityBudgetForms, checklists, rates and product info
Login
Login
Call: 13 RAMS
Home LoansHome Loans overviewHome loan interest ratesCompare our home loansFlexible featuresValue Advantage PackageFirst home buyersEssential home loanFixed rate home loansFull feature home loanLine of creditSelf-employedAll home loansRefinancersInvestorsCustomersSavings & TransactionsSavings & Transactions overviewRAMS SaverRAMS ActionRAMS Action with OffsetInsuranceKnowledge CentreKnowledge Centre overviewAll topicsBuilding a homeBuying a propertyInvestingManaging financesRefinancingRenovatingCalculators & ResourcesCalculators & Resources overviewAll calculatorsBorrowingRepaymentsStamp dutyUpfront & ongoing costsEquityBudgetForms, checklists, rates and product info
About RAMS
Contact us
Find us
Home LoansHome loan interest ratesCompare our home loansFlexible featuresValue Advantage PackageFirst home buyersEssential home loanFixed rate home loansFull feature home loanLine of creditSelf-employedAll home loansRefinancersInvestorsCustomersSavings & TransactionsRAMS SaverRAMS ActionRAMS Action with OffsetInsuranceKnowledge CentreAll topicsBuilding a homeBuying a propertyInvestingManaging financesRefinancingRenovatingCalculators & ResourcesAll calculatorsBorrowingRepaymentsStamp dutyUpfront & ongoing costsEquityBudgetForms, checklists, rates and product info
RAMSAbout RAMSPrivacy
About RAMS
About RAMS
Privacy policy
Privacy Policy
When you trust us with your personal information, you expect us to protect it and keep it safe.  Our privacy policy is shown below or you can view a summary of the policy, download the pdf version or contact us for a free printed version.
Download our Credit Reporting Policy and our Statement of Notifiable Matters.
We are bound by the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (‘Privacy Act’) and will protect your personal information in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles. These principles govern how we can collect, use, hold and disclose your personal information, as well as ensuring the quality and security of your personal information.
If you would like more information about how we protect your privacy, please contact us.
For our customers located in the European Union
From 25 May 2018, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) regulates the processing of personal information under European Union (EU) law. The GDPR aims to protect the information relating to individuals in the EU and harmonise data protection laws across EU Member States.
Our collection, use, disclosure and processing of your personal information is regulated by the GDPR if:
you interact with our Westpac UK branch;
we offer products or services to you whilst you are located in the EU; or
we monitor your behaviour whilst you are located in the EU.
Please refer to the Westpac group’s EU Data Protection Policy for information about how we manage your personal information under the GDPR.
About this policy
This privacy policy explains how we manage your personal information. Please refer to the Credit Reporting Policy for information on our management of your credit information.
What is personal information?
Personal information includes any information or opinion about an identified individual or an individual who can be reasonably identified from their information. The information or opinion will still be personal information whether it is true or not and regardless of whether we have kept a record of it.
The information that we seek to collect about you will depend on the products or services that we provide. If you do not allow us to collect all of the information we request, we may not be able to deliver all of those services effectively.
What kinds of personal information do we collect and hold?
When you apply for our products or services we may ask for identification information. This could include your name, address, contact details and date of birth. We may also collect your tax file number if we are authorised to collect it and if you choose to supply it. If you apply for insurance, we may collect information about what is being insured, the beneficiaries, and your health and financial situation, depending on the type of insurance.
Throughout the life of your product or service, we may collect and hold additional personal information about you. This could include transaction information or making a record of queries or complaints you make and, if you make an insurance claim, collecting additional information to assess the claim.
The collection of sensitive information is restricted by the Privacy Act. This includes information about your religion, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, criminal record, and sexual orientation. It also includes health information and biometric information.
Generally, we only collect this sort of information if it is necessary to provide you with a specific product or service and you have consented to that collection. For example, we may collect health information about you to process a claim under an insurance policy or collect voice biometric information to verify your identity or authorise transactions.
For what purposes do we collect, hold, use and disclose personal information?
The main reason we collect, use, hold and disclose personal information is to provide you with products and services. This includes:
checking whether you are eligible for the product or service;
assisting you where online applications are not completed;
providing the product or service; and
helping manage the product or service.
We may also use your information to comply with legislative or regulatory requirements in any jurisdiction, prevent fraud, crime or other activity that may cause harm in relation to our products or services and to help us run our business. We may also use your information to tell you about products or services we think may interest you.
How do we collect personal information?
We collect most personal information directly from you. For example, we will collect your personal information when you apply for or use a product or service or talk to us in person or on the phone.
We also collect information from you electronically. For instance, when you visit our website or whenever you apply for or access our products and services electronically (see "Do we collect personal information electronically?").
Sometimes we collect personal information about you from other people or organisations. This may happen without your direct involvement. For instance, we may collect personal information about you from:
other Westpac Group companies;
publicly available sources of information, such as public registers;
your representatives (including your legal adviser, mortgage broker, financial adviser, executor, administrator, guardian, trustee, or attorney);
your employer;
other organisations, who jointly with us, provide products or services to you;
commercial information service providers, such as companies that provide fraud prevention reports; and
insurers, re-insurers and health care providers.
What laws require or authorise us to collect personal information?
We are required or authorised to collect:
certain identification information about you by the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act 2006 (Cth) and Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Rules Instrument 2007 (No. 1);
your Tax File Number, if you choose to provide it, by the Income Tax Assessment Act 1936 (Cth);
if you have applied for credit or provide a guarantee, certain information about your financial position under the National Consumer Credit Protection Act 2009 (Cth), and if you give us a mortgage security, certain identification information under property laws in some states and territories; and
certain information in relation to your application if you have applied for insurance as required by the Insurance Contracts Act 1984 (Cth).
How do we hold personal information?
Much of the information we hold about you will be stored electronically in secure data centres which are located in Australia and owned by either the Westpac Group or external service providers. Some information we hold about you will be stored in paper files. We use a range of physical and electronic security measures to protect the security of the personal information we hold. For example:
access to information systems is controlled through identity and access management;
employees are bound by internal information security policies and are required to keep information secure;
all employees are required to complete training about information security;
we regularly monitor and review our compliance with internal policies and industry best practice; and
we take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify any personal information after it can no longer be used.
Who do we disclose your personal information to, and why?
We may share your personal information with other companies within the Westpac Group.  We may also provide personal information about our customers to organisations outside the Westpac Group. To protect personal information, we enter into contracts with our service providers that require them to comply with the Privacy Act. These contracts oblige them to only use the personal information we disclose to them for the specific role we ask them to perform.
Generally, we disclose personal information to organisations that help us with our business. These may include:
our agents, contractors and external service providers (for example, mailing houses and technology service providers);
authorised representatives and credit representatives who sell products and services on our behalf;
insurers, re-insurers and health care providers;
payment systems operators (for example, merchants receiving card payments);
other organisations, who jointly with us, provide products or services to you;
other financial services organisations, including banks, superannuation funds, stockbrokers, custodians, funds managers and portfolio service providers;
debt collectors;
financial advisers, legal advisers or auditors;
your representatives (including your legal adviser, accountant, mortgage broker, financial adviser, executor, administrator, guardian, trustee, or attorney);
fraud bureaus or other organisations to identify, investigate or prevent fraud or other misconduct;
external dispute resolution schemes; and
regulatory bodies, government agencies and law enforcement bodies in any jurisdiction.
We may also disclose your personal information to others outside the Westpac Group where:
we are required or authorised by law or where we have a public duty to do so;
you may have expressly consented to the disclosure or the consent may be reasonably inferred from the circumstances; or
we are otherwise permitted to disclose the information under the Privacy Act.
Do we disclose personal information overseas?
We may disclose your personal information to a recipient which is located outside Australia. This includes:
Westpac Group’s service providers which are likely to be located in New Zealand, India, the Philippines, China and the United States; and
for international transactions, such as currency exchanges, we may need to disclose your information to the corresponding international party in order to process the transaction. The countries we disclose your information to will depend on the details of the transaction you ask us to carry out.
Do we use other parties to collect and hold personal information?
In certain circumstances, other parties may collect and hold information on our behalf. For example:
If you apply for a product or service through a RAMS Home Loan Centre, the franchisee that operates that centre will collect your information on our behalf.
If you contact our call centre, the external service provider that operates the call centre will collect your information on our behalf.  We will exchange personal information about you with these parties and their employees.
Do we use or disclose personal information for marketing?
We will use your personal information to offer you products and services we believe may interest you, but we will not do so if you tell us not to. These products and services may be offered by a member of the Westpac Group or one of its preferred suppliers. We may offer you products and services by various means, including by mail, telephone, email, SMS or other electronic means , such as through social media or targeted advertising through Westpac Group or non-Westpac Group websites.
We may also disclose your personal information to RAMS franchisees and other companies outside the Westpac Group who assist us to market our products and services to you.
If you don’t want to receive marketing offers from us please contact us.
Do we collect personal information electronically?
We will collect information from you electronically, for instance through internet browsing, mobile or tablet applications.
Each time you visit the RAMS website, we collect information about your use of the website, which may include the following:
the date and time of visits;
which pages are viewed;
how users navigate through the site and interact with pages (including fields completed in forms and applications completed);
location information about users;
information about the device used to visit the RAMS website; and
IP addresses.
We use technology called cookies when you visit the RAMS site. Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your hard drive or in memory. They can record information about your visit to the site, allowing it to remember you the next time you visit and provide a more meaningful experience.
One of the reasons for using cookies is to offer you increased security. The cookies we send to your computer cannot read your hard drive, obtain any information from your browser or command your computer to perform any action. They are designed so that they cannot be sent to another site, or be retrieved by any non-Westpac Group site.
We won't ask you to supply personal information publicly over Facebook, Twitter, or any other social media platform that we use. Sometimes we may invite you to send your details to us via private messaging, for example, to answer a question about your account. You may also be invited to share your personal information through secure channels to participate in other activities, such as competitions.
Access to and correction of personal information
You can request access to the personal information we hold about you. You can also ask for corrections to be made. To do so, please contact us.
There is no fee for requesting that your personal information is corrected or for us to make corrections. In processing your request for access to your personal information, a reasonable cost may be charged. This charge covers such things as locating the information and supplying it to you.  There are some circumstances in which we are not required to give you access to your personal information.
If we refuse to give you access to or to correct your personal information we will give you a notice explaining our reasons except where it would be unreasonable to do so.
If we refuse your request to correct your personal information, you also have the right to request that a statement be associated with your personal information noting that you disagree with its accuracy.
If we refuse your request to access or correct your personal information, we will also provide you with information on how you can complain about the refusal.
Notifiable data breaches
From February 2018, the Privacy Act includes a Notifiable Data Breaches (NDB) scheme which requires us to notify you and the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC) of certain data breaches and recommend steps you can take to limit the impacts of a breach (for example, a password change).
The NDB scheme requires us to notify about a data breach that is likely to result in serious harm to affected individuals. There are exceptions where notification is not required.  For example, where we have already taken appropriate remedial action that removes the risk of serious harm to any individuals.
If we believe there has been a data breach that impacts your personal information and creates a likely risk of serious harm, we will notify you and the OAIC as soon as practicable and keep in close contact with you about the nature of the breach, the steps we are taking and what you can do to reduce the impacts to your privacy.
If you believe that any personal information we hold about you has been impacted by a data breach, you can Contact us using the contact details below.
Resolving your privacy concerns and complaints – your rights
If you are concerned about how your personal information is being handled or if you have a complaint about a breach by us of the Australian Privacy Principles, please contact us.
We will acknowledge your complaint as soon as we can after receipt of your complaint. We will let you know if we need any further information from you to resolve your complaint.
We aim to resolve complaints as quickly as possible. We strive to resolve complaints within five business days but some complaints take longer to resolve. If your complaint is taking longer, we will let you know what is happening and a date by which you can reasonably expect a response.
If you are not satisfied with our response, you may be able to lodge a complaint with the Australian Financial Complaints Authority (AFCA).  AFCA can consider certain privacy complaints  relating to either the provision of credit or credit reporting information in general.  AFCA can be contacted at:
Online: www.afca.org.au
Email:
info@afca.org.au
Phone: 1800 931 678
Mail: Australian Financial Complaints Authority GPO Box 3, Melbourne VIC 3001
Under the Privacy Act you may complain to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner about the way we handle your credit information.
The Commissioner can be contacted at:
GPO Box 5218
Sydney NSW 2001
Phone: 1300 363 992
Email: enquiries@oaic.gov.au
www.oaic.gov.au
Contact us
You can contact us or our Privacy Officer by:
calling 13 RAMS, that’s 13 7267
emailing privacy_officer@ramsservices.com.au
visiting our website RAMS.com.au
visiting a RAMS Home Loan Centre
writing to us at Locked Bag 5001, Concord West, NSW 2138
Changes to the Privacy Policy
We may change the way we handle personal information from time to time for any reason. If we do so, we will update this Privacy Policy. An up-to-date version is available on RAMS.com.au
Meaning of words
RAMS means RAMS Financial Group Pty Limited (ABN 30 105 207 538) – a wholly owned subsidiary of Westpac Banking Corporation (ABN 33 007 457 141).
We, us or our means:
RAMS Financial Group Pty Limited
Westpac Banking Corporation in its capacity as the credit provider for RAMS home loans and issuer of RAMS deposit products
Westpac General Insurance Limited (ABN 99 003 719 319) in its capacity as the issuer of RAMS Home and Contents Insurance and RAMS Landlord Insurance
St. George Life Limited (ABN 88 076 763 936) in its capacity as the issuer of RAMS Home Loan Protection Insurance
as the context dictates.
Westpac Group means Westpac Banking Corporation and its related bodies corporate
RAMS Financial Group Pty Ltd ABN 30 105 207 538 AR 405465 Australian credit licence 388065. Credit Provider: Westpac Banking Corporation ABN 33 007 457 141 AFSL and Australian credit licence 233714. Updated 1 November 2018.
Meet with us
Have us call you
Compare all home loans
Find local expert
Meet with us
Have us call you
Calculators
×
Modal title
Hello world! I'm the modal body
Close
Save changes
×
Meet with us
For help regarding hardship as a result of COVID-19 please complete our assistance form.
Your local RAMS home loan specialist is here to help.
Leave your details and your local RAMS Home Loan Specialist will be in touch.
First name:
Last name:
Postcode:
Email:
Contact number:
Your loan needs: *
Please select...
Buying or building your first home
Buying or building a home to live in
Buying or building an investment property
Refinancing my home loan
Consolidate your debt into one easy loan
Looking to change my existing RAMS loan
Employment status: *
Please select...
Employed (PAYG)
Self-employed
Retired
Other (home duties, student, not working)
Any comments?:
I would like to be included on the list to receive information about property news, articles, tips, products and services from RAMS and its franchisees.
By submitting this form you acknowledge that you have read and accept our
privacy statement
Would you like RAMS and its franchisees to keep you informed about products and services including via email?
×
Find your local RAMS Home Loan Centre
×
RAMS Mobile Service
Please call 13 RAMS that’s 13 7267 and a RAMS Mobile Home Loan Specialist will give you a call and come out to discuss your home loan needs with you.
If you’d like we can call you back. Just click on the ‘Have us Call You’ button, enter your number and we’ll be in touch soon.
Alternatively, you can try submitting a different region or postcode.
×
Privacy statement
The personal information collected from you on this form will be used to respond to your query, and to provide you with information about the products and services we offer. We may disclose your personal information to RAMS and its franchisees, other members of the Westpac Group, anyone we engage to do something on our behalf, and other organisations that assist us with our business. Our privacy policy, available at rams.com.au or by calling 13 7267, contains information about how we handle your personal information.
Close
×
We are currently experiencing a high call volume. For help regarding hardship as a result of COVID-19 please complete our assistance form.
Have us call you
Enter your full phone number below and a RAMS Consultant will call you back at the time of your choice.
Full phone number*
Requires full phone number including area code
Call back *
Saturday
Sunday
Call back time*
Call now
10am - 11am
Request a call back
Currently requesting your call.
Thank you for your request for a call back.
You will soon receive a call from us on
You will receive a call from us between
9am – 10am on
(02) 9000 0000
Close
Unfortunately, our call back facility
is not available at the moment.
Please call us on 13RAMS that's 137267 or fill in our contact form and we will be in contact within two business hours.
We apologise for the inconvenience.
Our call centre is currently closed.
Please see our contact us page for opening hours.
The RAMS team
Close
Please be advised we collect and use your personal information to process your request. We may disclose your personal information to our related companies, franchisees and third parties who assist with our business. Our privacy policy is available on the RAMS website, it covers how we collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information, as well as how you can access or correct it. To help improve our service, this call may be recorded and you'll be able to leave feedback at the end of the call.
i
Close
